Faran Masood Peerzada

Address:

College of Electrical and Mechanical Engineering ,NUST, Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Phone:

+923005078036

Email:

Faranpeerzada253@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Passionate Computer Engineer with 3+ years of expertise working with Embedded Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Remote Sensing technologies. Eager to offer superb analytical and computer programming skills to produce robust code to implement machine learning solutions.

EXPERIENCE

- Centre of Agriculture and Bioscience International (CABI) Regional Research Centre, Rawalpindi, Pakistan
 - Working as a Consultant for IT and Digital Tool development under Project titled "Plantwise Plus"

Key Responsibilities:

- Designing and developing analysis systems to extract information from large-scale data.
- Development of Plantwise Web Dashboard.
- Applying data mining to Harmonize Plantwise e-clinic data.
- Implementing Machine learning techniques on Plantwise data to acquire desired results.
- Worked as a Machine Learning Expert on a Project titled "Mapping and Estimating Parthenium hysterophorus using Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Imagery in District Peshawar" Key Responsibilities:
 - Stitched UAV data to acquire mosaics using OpenCV and Python scripts.
 - Collected Hi-resolution data using Drone.
 - Calibrated Hi-resolution Multispectral Sensor.
 - Labeled and processed data using Machine learning algorithms.
- Worked as Research Assistant on a Project "Remote Sensing Parthenium in Pakistan"
 Key Responsibilities:
 - Developed field maps to collect High-resolution data using a DJI Matrice 100.
 - Developed a pipeline for Stitching Multispectral data using OpenCV and Python.
 - Processed Data using Machine learning algorithms.
- National Internship Program, Pakistan
 - Teaching Assistantship
 Computer Vision with Dr. Wagar Shahid

July 2021 - Continue

October 2020 - June 2021

May 2019 - September 2020

June 2017 - July 2018

EDUCATION

 National University of Sciences and Technology, College of E&ME, Islamabad, Pakistan September 2017 – November 2020

MS Mechatronics Engineering

- Area of concentration: Machine Learning, Machine Vision, Remote Sensing, Robotics
- Thesis: Evaluation of High-Resolution Airborne Imagery for Mapping Invasive Weeds in Crops
- Advisor: Dr Waqar Shahid Qureshi
- CGPA: 3.65/4.00

 The Islamia University of Bahawalpur, University College of Engineering and Technology, Bahawalpur, Pakistan **September 2012 – July 2016**

BSc Computer Systems Engineering

- Area of concentration: Image Processing and Robotics
- FYP project: Human Presence-Based Auto Switching of Room Appliances to Save Energy
- CGPA: 3.46/4.0

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- **Programming Languages:** Python, C++, JavaScript, MATLAB.
- **Programming Tools:** Visual Studio Code, PyCharm, Anaconda, Git, Adobe Dream viewer.
- Image Stitching Tools: WebODM, Zephyr Aerial.
- **Python Packages:** Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, Keras, Matplotlib, Seaborn, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Tableau.
- Web Development using: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Bootstrap, and WordPress.
- Framework: Django.
- **Drones:** Phantom series, Mavic Series, Matrice 100.
- Remote Sensing Tools: QGIS and ArcGIS.
- Publication Tools: LaTeX, Visio, MS Office.
- Application in Machine Learning:
 - Logistic Regression. Dimensionality Reduction
 - Linear Regression. Image Classification
 - Decision Tree. Object Detection
 - SVM Algorithm. Clustering
 - CNN Algorithm.
 Data Modeling,

- Predictive Modeling
- Classification
- KNN Algorithm.
- Random Forest Algorithm.

Certifications

- CCNA (Routing and Switching) from CORVIT Systems, Lahore, Pakistan.
- Linux (RHCSA) from CORVIT Systems, Lahore, Pakistan.
- Web Development using PHP from Aptech Bahawalpur, Pakistan

Course Projects

- M.Sc. Course Project
 - Smart touch pen for smart devices
- B.Sc. Course Project
 - RDBMS Web-based tutorial using HTML, CSS, PHP
 - Coursework record-keeping system using C++

Languages

- English [Proficient]
- Urdu [Native]

References

- Dr. Waqar Shahid Qureshi, Assistant Professor
 National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad Pakistan waqar.shahid@alumni.ait.asia
- Dr. Joseph Fennell, Postdoctoral Research Associate
 Jodrell Bank Centre for Astrophysics, University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom
 joseph.fennell@manchester.ac.uk
- Rene Breton, Professor of Astrophysics
 Jodrell Bank Centre for Astrophysics, University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom rene.breton@manchester.ac.uk
- Dr. Muhammad Usman, Assistant Professor
 Centre for Geographical Information System, University of the Punjab Lahore, Pakistan Muhammadusman.gis@pu.edu.pk